doorbird.com 2017-06-06

# The smartphone and tablet IP Video Door Station for iOS and Android

Privacy policy This Privacy Policy is intended to help you understand how Bird Home Automation GmbH its subsidiaries and affiliates ("Bird Home Automation," "we," "us" or “our”) collect, use and safeguard the information you provide with us on this website or through our Services (as defined in our “Terms of Use”). By using or accessing our Services, you signify your acknowledgment and assent to the Privacy Policy set forth below. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Services. Bird Home Automation can revise this policy at any time by updating this posting, and your use after such change signifies your acceptance of the changed terms. Please check this policy periodically for changes. 

### Collection of personal information

If you browse the Bird Home Automation website, you may generally do so anonymously without providing any personal information. However, there are cases in which we may ask you for personal data. For example, we will occasionally conduct on-line surveys to better understand the needs and profile of our visitors. In addition, we may request personal information when you register to receive additional information regarding our products and services, download software, sign up for a newsletter or send us a question. Even if you choose not to give information we request, you can still visit most of the Bird Home Automation website, but you may be unable to access certain options, offers and services. In case you change your mind or wish to update or delete personal information, we will endeavor to correct, update or remove the personal data you give us. You can do this by contacting us at the contact specified below. 

### Your device

For reasons of brevity, we use the terms "device" to refer to our "DoorBird Video Door Station" and "BirdGuard" products and "mobile device" to refer to a smartphone or tablet.   
_Information input during setup:_ When you install your device, you may be asked for certain basic information like your device name, description, ZIP or postal code, as well as where you’re installing it. This information is used to personalize your experience – for example, to tell you which device is triggering a notification.   
_Environmental data from device sensors:_ We collect data from sensors built into DoorBird Video Door Stations / BirdGuard cameras. These sensors collect data such as device temperature and ambient light. By recording this information, device can know, for instance, whether it’s dark and it should turn on night vision.   
_Video and audio signals and data:_ After you begin using your device, we may process information from your device so that we can send you alerts when your doorbell is pressed or when your device detects motion. This may include capturing and emailing to you portions of this data as part of a notification or analyzing the data to identify motion or other events. When you access our Cloud Service on a trial basis or a subscription basis, we will record and process video and/or audio recordings from your device. In addition, we will capture, process and retain video and audio data recordings from your device for the duration of your recording subscription period and you will be able to access those recordings using the Services during that time.   
_Technical information from the device:_ In order to improve your experience over time and help troubleshoot any problem you may encounter with device, we may record your device serial number, software version, and technical information such as Wi-Fi signal strength.   
_Saved and Shared Content:_ You may save and may choose to share certain content like video clips, images, captions, and comments for other people to access using the Services. We will collect and store information that will allow us to save or share your content as directed by you through the Services. 

Data protection and privacy laws in your country may impose certain responsibilities on you and your use of the device. You are responsible for ensuring that you comply with any applicable laws when you use the device. For example, you may need to display a notice that alerts visitors to your home that you are using the device. Note in particular that recording and sharing clips that involve other people may affect their privacy and data protection rights. Also check the data privacy information in the installation manual of your device. 

### Orders

When you place an order for a product or service, we need to know your name, e-mail address, mailing address, credit card number and expiration date. This personal information is required so that we can process and fulfill your order, send an order or shipping confirmation, as well as notify you of your order status. Also, once you place an order, we may send you informational emails about our products and services, including promotional offers. If you do not wish to receive such emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by emailing us at hello@doorbird.com. Also, once you place an order or make an inquiry regarding our products, we may send you informational emails about our products and services, including promotional offers. If you do not wish to receive such emails from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by emailing us at hello@doorbird.com. 

### Bird Home Automations Mailings/Marketing Communications

If you provide us with personal information, we may place you on our company’s email list to receive email regarding product/service updates, special offers, important issues and new products and services offered by Bird Home Automation and its affiliates. If you do not wish to receive email updates or other marketing communications from our company or our affiliates, you may unsubscribe at any time by contacting us at hello@doorbird.com. 

### Use of personal information

Personal information provided by users may be used for marketing and promotional purposes only by Bird Home Automation and its subsidiaries and affiliates. Except as described in this policy, Bird Home Automation does not rent, sell or otherwise distribute to third parties, your personal information entered on this site without your consent, unless required by law or as disclosed to you when the information is collected. If you do provide us with consent to share your information with other third party companies, we may share your information with third party companies who offer products and services that may be of interest to you. These companies may then contact you directly with product or sample offers, personalized offers and information, or to ask for your feedback on products and programs that they think may be of interest to you. While we use all reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your information, Bird Home Automation will have no liability for disclosure of any information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties. We may share your personal information with our third party service providers on a need- to-know basis. We engage third party service providers to perform certain services on our behalf. In order to perform those services, the service providers may need to know your personal information. We require that they protect this information and only use it to perform services on our behalf. For example, we may use outside shipping companies, credit card processing companies, resellers, distributors and content providers. We may share statistical or aggregated non-personal information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties. This data is used to customize Bird Home Automation website content and advertising to deliver a better experience to our users. 

### Cookies and tracking

This site may use cookies for site administration purposes. If for any reason you wish to not take advantage of cookies, you may have your browser not accept them, although this may disable or render unusable some of the features of the Bird Home Automation website. This website also may detect and use your IP address or domain name for internal traffic monitoring and capacity purposes or to otherwise administer our website. No personal information is obtained; rather, just the patterns of usage of our various users may be tracked to provide you with improved service and content based on aggregate or statistical reviews of user site traffic patterns. 

### Special cases

Bird Home Automation reserves the right to disclose user information in special cases, when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) our rights or property, other Bird Home Automation website users or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. We may disclose personal information without notice to you in response to a subpoena or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or to respond to an emergency situation. 

### Policies for children

The features, programs, promotions and other aspects of this website requiring personal information are not intended for children. Bird Home Automation does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 and believe he or she has disclosed personal information to us, please notify at the contact point specified below. A parent or guardian of a child under the age of 18 may review and request deletion of such child’s personal information. 

### Linked Sites

Please be advised that this website may contain links to third party websites. The linked sites are not under the control of Bird Home Automation, and we are not responsible for the contents or privacy practices of any linked site or any link on a linked site. 

### Changes to the privacy policy

Bird Home Automation reserves the right to change or update this policy, or any other policy or practice, at any time, with reasonable notice to users of this website. Any changes or updates will be effective immediately upon posting to the Bird Home Automation site. Bird Home Automation GmbH  
Joachimsthaler Str. 12  
10719 Berlin  
Germany  
Effective: September 30, 2015
